Guide to the Duke Players Records, 1930-1986 UA.31.07.0008
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke Players records
1930-1986
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. Duke Players
UA.31.07.0008
10 Linear Feet
Duke University's Duke Players was founded in February 1931, with the intention of providing students with the opportunity to participate in all aspects of theater. Records include production files, news clippings, press releases, newsletters, posters, and scrapbooks.
Historical note
Duke University's Duke Players was founded in February 1931, replacing the defunct Taurian Players, a coed dramatic group established in 1924. The intention of the Duke Players was (and is) to provide students with the opportunity to participate in all aspects of theater, including acting, directing, and production. Though established when the Women's College was still in existence, female students joined male students in all areas of production. The Duke Players is completely student run, though it does have a faculty representative.
Scope and Contents
Records include production files, news clippings, press releases, newsletters, posters, and scrapbooks. Materials range in date from 1930 to 1986.
Provenance
The Duke Players records were received by the Duke University Archives as multiple transfers between 1977 and 1985, 2014.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
College theater; Duke University. Duke Players; Duke University--Students
- Duke Players records, 1930-1986; 1
  - After Magritte (Box 1)
  - After the Fall (Box 1)
  - Androcles and the Lion (Box 1)
  - Angel Street (Box 1)
  - Another Part of the Forest (Box 1)
  - Antigone (Box 1)
  - Arms and the Man (Box 1)
  - Arsenic and Old Lace (Box 1)
  - The Ascent of F9 (Box 1)
  - As You Like It (Box 1)
  - "The Avant-Garde Theatre of Ionesco"- A Lecture (Box 1)
  - Bad Habits (Box 1)
  - The Balcony (Box 1)
  - The Bald Soprano (Box 1)
  - The Bat (Box 1)
  - The Bear (Box 1)
  - Bell, Book and Candle (Box 1)
  - Birthday Party (Box 1)
  - The Bishop of Mishigasi (Box 1)
  - Blithe Spirit (Box 1)
  - Blood Wedding (Box 1)
  - Born Yesterday, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Boy Meets Girl (Box 1)
  - Brecht on Brecht (Box 1)
  - Brief Music (Box 1)
  - The Captive (Box 1)
  - Cat on a Hot Tin Roof (Box 1)
  - Claudia (Box 1)
  - The Comedy of Errors (Box 1)
  - The Corinthian, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - The Crucible (Box 1)
  - Dark of the Moon (Box 1)
  - Dear Ruth (Box 1)
  - Death of a Salesman (Box 1)
  - Desire Under the Elms (Box 1)
  - The Double Doors (Box 1)
  - The Drunkard (Box 1)
  - Equus (Box 1)
  - Erasmus (Box 1)
  - Eve of St. Mark (Box 1)
  - Everyman (Box 1)
  - Family Portrait (Box 1)
  - The Fantasticks (Box 1)
  - The Father (Box 1)
  - Feiffer's People (Box 1)
  - Finian's Rainbow (Box 1)
  - Firebugs (Box 1)
  - "Five One-Act Tragedies", Mirage, The Valiant, Four on a Hearth, Bitter Herbs, Theatre of the Soul, 1937 (Box 1)
  - The Flies (Box 1)
  - "From Reality" (Box 1)
  - The Front Page (Box 1)
  - Galileo (Box 1)
  - The Gallery (Box 1)
  - The Ghost Train (Box 1)
  - The Glass Menagerie (Box 1)
  - The Glass Slipper (Box 1)
  - God (Box 1)
  - Great Catherine (Box 1)
  - "A Group of Laboratory Productions" (Box 1)
  - Hansel and Gretel (Box 1)
  - Happy Birthday, Wanda June (Box 1)
  - Harvey (Box 1)
  - Hayfoot, Strawfoot (Box 1)
  - Heartbreak House (Box 1)
  - Hedda Gabler (Box 1)
  - Henry IV (Box 2)
  - Here We Are (Box 2)
  - Hiawatha (Box 2)
  - The Hostage (Box 2)
  - The Hotel Baltimore (Box 2)
  - Hotel Universe (Box 2)
  - Humpty Dumpty (Box 2)
  - Imaginary Invalid (Box 2)
  - The Importance of Being Earnest (Box 2)
  - The Importance of Being Earnest (#2) (Box 2)
  - Impromptu (Box 2)
  - Infernal Machine (Box 2)
  - The Intellectual Ladies (Box 2)
  - The Interdict (Box 2)
  - Jacques Brel is Alive and Well and Living in Paris (Box 2)
  - J.B. (Box 2)
  - John Loves Mary (Box 2)
  - Journey's End (Box 2)
  - Julius Caesar (Box 2)
  - Key Largo (Box 2)
  - Kind Lady (Box 2)
  - Kiss Me Kate (Box 2)
  - Krapp's Last Tape (Box 2)
  - Ladies in Retirement (Box 2)
  - Ladies of the Jury (Box 2)
  - The Lady's Not for Burning (Box 2)
  - The Late George Apley (Box 2)
  - The Lesson (Box 2)
  - Light Up the Sky (Box 2)
  - The Little Foxes (Box 2)
  - Little Murders (Box 2)
  - A Look Back in Anger, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - The Lover (Box 2)
  - Love's Labors Lost (Box 2)
  - Lysistrata (Box 2)
  - Macbeth (Box 2)
  - The Madwoman of Chaillot (Box 2)
  - The Maids (Box 2)
  - The Male Animal, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - The Man Who Came to Dinner (Box 2)
  - Marat/Sade (Box 2)
  - Marco Millions, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Margin for Error (Box 2)
  - Measure for Measure (Box 2)
  - The Medium (Box 2)
  - The Merchant of Venice (Box 2)
  - "A Mime" (Box 2)
  - Misalliance (Box 2)
  - The Misanthrope (Box 2)
  - The Miser (Box 2)
  - "Miss Julie" (Box 2)
  - Moliere Festival, 1973 (Box 2)
  - The Moon is Blue (Box 2)
  - "Mr. Flannery's Ocean" (Box 2)
  - Much Ado About Nothing (Box 2)
  - My Sister Eileen (Box 2)
  - My 3 Angels (Box 2)
  - Night Must Fall (Box 2)
  - The Ninth Guest (Box 2)
  - No Exit (Box 2)
  - No Mother to Guide Her (Box 2)
  - Our Town (Box 2)
  - Othello (Box 2)
  - Past Grand Night (Box 2)
  - Personal Appearance (Box 2)
  - Petticoat Fever (Box 2)
  - A Phoenix Too Frequent (Box 2)
  - Pink Lady (Box 2)
  - The Playboy of the Western World (Box 2)
  - The Pleasure of His Company, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - "The Private Ear" (Box 2)
  - The Private Life of the Master Race (Box 2)
  - The Provincial Lady (Box 2)
  - Pullman Car (Box 2)
  - Pygmalion (Box 2)
  - Rashomon (Box 2)
  - Reclining Figure (Box 2)
  - Remains to be Seen, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Rhinoceros (Box 2)
  - Richard II (Box 2)
  - Right You Are (Box 2)
  - Ring Round the Moon (Box 2)
  - The Roman Kid (Box 3)
  - Room Service (Box 3)
  - Rosencrantz and Guildenstern Are Dead (Box 3)
  - The Royal Hunt of the Sun (Box 3)
  - The Sandbox (Box 3)
  - "Scenes from Opera" (Box 3)
  - The School for Scandal, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - The School for Scandal - scenes from (Box 3)
  - The Seagull (Box 3)
  - Shadow and Substance (Box 3)
  - Six Characters in Search of an Author (Box 3)
  - The Skin of Our Teeth, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Snafu (Box 3)
  - Snowangel (Box 3)
  - The Song of Bernadette (Box 3)
  - Spreading the News (Box 3)
  - Spring Dance (Box 3)
  - Stage Door (Box 3)
  - Story Theatre (Box 3)
  - A Streetcar Named Desire, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - A Study in Sin (Box 3)
  - Summer and Smoke (Box 3)
  - The Taming of the Shrew (Box 3)
  - Tango (Box 3)
  - The Teahouse of the August Moon (Box 3)
  - The Tempest (Box 3)
  - Ten Little Indians (Box 3)
  - Ten Nights in a Barroom (Box 3)
  - Therese (Box 3)
  - This Property is Condemned (Box 3)
  - A Thousand Clowns (Box 3)
  - Three Men on a Horse (Box 3)
  - The Threepenny Opera, 1964 (Box 3)
  - The Threepenny Opera, 1976 (Box 3)
  - The Tiger (Box 3)
  - Tiger at the Gates (Box 3)
  - The Time of Your Life (Box 3)
  - The Torch-Bearers (Box 3)
  - Toys in the Attic (Box 3)
  - Travesties (Box 3)
  - A Triangle in the Square (Box 11)
  - Twelfth Night (Box 3)
  - Twelfth Night-readings (Box 3)
  - The Ugly Duckling (Box 3)
  - Uncle Harry (Box 3)
  - Uncle Vanya (Box 3)
  - Uncommon Women and Others (Box 3)
  - Venus Observed (Box 3)
  - Volpone (Box 3)
  - Waiting for Godot (Box 3)
  - Water Spiders (Box 3)
  - Ways of Life (Box 3)
  - The What-Not (Box 3)
  - What the Butler Saw (Box 3)
  - Who's Afraid of Virginia Woolf? (Box 3)
  - Wind in the Willows (Box 3)
  - Winterset (Box 3)
  - The Winter's Tale (Box 3)
  - Yes is for a Very Young Man (Box 3)
  - The Youngest (Box 3)
  - The Zoo Story, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - 1934-35 Season (Box 3)
  - 1952-53 Season (Box 3)
  - 1953-54 Season (Box 3)
  - 1970-71 Season (Box 3)
  - 1970-71 Season News Clippings (Box 3)
  - 1972-73 Season (Box 3)
  - 1972-73 Season News Clippings (Box 3)
  - 1973-74 Season News Clippings (Box 3)
  - 1974-75 Season (Box 3)
  - 1974-75 Season News Clippings (Box 3)
  - 1975-76 Season (Box 3)
  - 1976-77 Season (Box 3)
  - 1976-77 Season News Clippings (Box 3)
  - 1977-78 Season (Box 3)
  - 1977-78 Season News Clippings (Box 3)
  - 1978-79 Season (Box 3)
  - 1978-79 Season News Clippings (Box 3)
  - 1979-80 Season (Box 3)
  - 1979-80 Season News Clippings (Box 3)
  - 1980-81 Season (Box 3)
  - 1980-81 Season News Clippings (Box 3)
  - 1981-82 Season (Box 3)
  - 1981-82 Season News Clippings (Box 3)
  - Theater Newsletters 1982 (Box 3)
  - 1982-83 Season (Box 4)
  - 1982-83 PSA's (Box 4)
  - 1982-83 News Releases (Box 4)
  - 1982-83 Season News Clippings (Box 4)
  - 1982-83 Publicity Letters (Box 4)
  - 1983-84 Season (Box 4)
  - 1983-84 Season News Clippings (Box 4)
  - 1984-85 Season (Box 4)
  - 1984-85 Season News Clippings (Box 4)
  - 1985-86 Season (Box 4)
  - Publicity Aids, Guides (Box 4)
  - Scrapbooks, 1930-1933 (Box 5)
  - Scrapbooks, 1933-1941 (Box 5)
  - Scrapbooks, 1934-46 (Box 6)
  - Scrapbooks, 1951-61 (Box 6)
  - Scrapbooks, 1971-72 (Box 6)
  - Scrapbooks, 1972-73 (Box 6)
  - Scrapbooks, 1973-74 (Box 7)
  - Scrapbooks, 1974-75 (Box 7)
  - Scrapbooks, 1975-76 (Box 7)
  - Scrapbooks, 1976-77 (Box 7)
  - The Lesson (Box 8)
  - Man of La Mancha (Box 8)
  - [untitled], 1975-1976 (Box 8)
  - Dark of the Moon (Box 8)
  - The Imaginary Invalid (Box 8)
  - Importance of Being Earnest, 1959 (Box 8)
  - Importance of Being Earnest, 1952 (Box 8)
  - Importance of Being Earnest, 1975 (Box 8)
  - Intellectual Ladies, 1973 (Box 8)
  - The Interdict (Box 8)
  - Jacques Brel, 1974 (Box 8)
  - J.B., 1972 (Box 8)
  - John Loves Mary (Box 8)
  - Krapp's Last Tape, 1968 (Box 8)
  - Ladies in Retirement, 1942 (Box 8)
  - The Lady's Not for Burning (Box 8)
  - The Late George Apley, 1948 (Box 8)
  - The Lesson, 1968 (Box 8)
  - The Little Foxes, 1976 (Box 8)
  - Death of a Salesman, 1960 (Box 8)
  - Deathwatch, 1973 (Box 8)
  - Eve of St. Mark (Box 8)
  - Fresh-Soph Shows, 1975 (Box 8)
  - Fresh-Soph Production, 1976 (Box 8)
  - Glass Menagerie, 1963 (Box 8)
  - The Ghost Train (Box 8)
  - Happy Birthday, Wanda June, 1977 (Box 8)
  - Harvey (Box 8)
  - Heartbreak House, 1971 (Box 8)
  - Henry IV, 1965 (Box 8)
  - The Persecution and Assassination of Jean-Paul Marat as Performed by the Inmates of the Asylum of Charenton under the Direction of the Marquis de Sade, 1969 (Box 8)
  - The Male Animal, 1947 (Box 8)
  - The Hostage, 1973 (Box 8)
  - Love's Labour's Lost, 1970 (Box 8)
  - Lysistrata, 1970 (Box 8)
  - Luv, 1971 (Box 8)
  - The Madwoman of Chaillot, 1972 (Box 8)
  - Macbeth, 1959 (Box 8)
  - Unidentified (Box 8)
  - Whiting, B.J. (Box 8)
  - Ceiling Zero (Box 8)
  - Cat on a Hot Tin Roof, 1972 (Box 8)
  - Cradle Song (Box 8)
  - The Crucible (Box 8)
  - The Corinthians, 1973 (Box 8)
  - Summer Theatre, 1973 (Box 8)
  - Marco Millions, 1950 (Box 8)
  - Margin for Error (Box 8)
  - Miss Julie (Box 8)
  - My Sister Eileen, 1943 (Box 8)
  - My Three Angels (Box 8)
  - Much Ado About Nothing, 1964 (Box 8)
  - Night Must Fall, 1938 (Box 8)
  - No Exit, 1968 (Box 8)
  - Othello, 1950 (Box 8)
  - Outward Bound, 1932 (Box 8)
  - Birthday Party, 1975 (Box 8)
  - Blithe Spirit, 1974 (Box 8)
  - Box and Cox (Box 8)
  - The Hostage, 1973 (Box 8)
  - Brecht on Brecht, 1969 (Box 8)
  - The Balcony, 1970 (Box 8)
  - Brief Music (Box 8)
  - School for Scandal, 1966 (Box 8)
  - Shadow and Substance, Six Characters in Search of an Author (Box 8)
  - The Skin of Our Teeth (Box 8)
  - Spring Dance (Box 8)
  - Story Theater (Box 8)
  - A Streetcar Named Desire (Box 8)
  - Summer and Smoke (Box 8)
  - Taming of the Shrew (Box 8)
  - Tango, 1970 (Box 8)
  - Teahouse of the August Moon, 1957 (Box 8)
  - The Tempest, 1972 (Box 8)
  - Ten Nights in a Barroom, 1942 (Box 8)
  - A Thousand Years Ago, 1933 (Box 8)
  - Three Men on A Horse, 1937-1938 (Box 8)
  - Three Penny Opera, 1964 (Box 8)
  - Three Penny Opera, 1976 (Box 8)
  - Tiger at the Gates (Box 8)
  - The Time of Your Life (Box 8)
  - The Torch-Bearers (Box 8)
  - Twelfth Night, 1969 (Box 8)
  - Type cast and Water spiders (Box 8)
  - Up Pops the Devil, 1934-1935 (Box 8)
  - Volpone (Box 8)
  - Waiting for Godot, 1972 (Box 8)
  - Ways of Life and Bishop of Mishigasi, 1977 (Box 8)
  - What the Butler Saw, 1975 (Box 8)
  - The What-Not and How Could I Not be Among You? 1975 (Box 8)
  - Wind in the Willows, 1973 (Box 8)
  - Winterset, 1940 (Box 8)
  - Zoo Story, 1968; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Zoo Story and The American Dream, 1964 (Box 8)
  - Zoo Story and Snowangel, 1974 (Box 8)
  - Studio Theatre, 1974-1975 (Box 8)
  - [loose photographs] (Box 8)
  - Unidentified photographs (Box 8)
  - Various playbills (Box 9)
  - Misc. [flyers, clippings] (Box 9)
  - Zoo Story and Snowangel, 1974 (Box 9)
  - A Streetcar Named Desire, 1973 (Box 9)
  - Blithe Spirit, 1974 (Box 9)
  - 1974-1975 Season (Box 9)
  - After the Fall, 1974-1975 (Box 9)
  - Jacques Brel is alive and well and living in Paris, 1974 (Box 9)
  - The Importance of Being Earnest, 1974 (Box 9)
  - The What Not and How Could I Not be Among You, 1975 (Box 9)
  - What the Butler Saw, 1975 (Box 9)
  - 1975-1976 Season (Box 9)
  - The Hot L Baltimore (Box 9)
  - 1970-1971 Season (Box 9)
  - Lysistrata, 1970 (Box 9)
  - 1971-1972 Season (Box 9)
  - Moliere's Scenes (Box 9)
  - The Tempest tryout sheets (Box 9)
  - 1972-1973 Season (Box 9)
  - Madwoman of Challiot (Box 9)
  - Cat on a Hot Tin Roof (Box 9)
  - Deathwatrch (Box 9)
  - Fresh-Soph Production, 1976 (Box 9)
  - The Little Foxes (Box 9)
  - The Persecution and Assassination of Jean-Paul Marat as Performed by the Inmates of the Asylum of Charenton under the Direction of the Marquis de Sade, 1977 (Box 9)
  - Happy Birthday, Wanda June (Box 9)
  - The Intellectual Ladies, 1972 (Box 9)
  - Type Cast and Water Spiders (Box 9)
  - Ways of Life and Bishop of Mishigasi (Box 9)
  - Little Murders, 1973 (Box 9)
  - Playbills -samples (Box 9)
  - 1973-1974 Season (Box 9)
  - Birthday Party (Box 9)
  - Fresh-Soph Shorts, 1975 (Box 9)
  - The Magic Flute, 1975 (Box 9)
  - The Imaginary Invalid (Box 9)
  - The Interdict (Box 9)
  - Bad Habits (Box 9)
  - Story Theatre (Box 9)
  - The Penny Opera, 1976 (Box 9)
  - A Phoenix Too Frequent, 1964 (Box 9)
  - Playboy of the Western World (Box 9)
  - The Pleasure of his Company, 1963 (Box 9)
  - Private Ear, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Rhinoceros, 1971-1972 (Box 9)
  - Rhinoceros, 1971 (Box 9)
  - Richard II, 1962 (Box 9)
  - Right You Are (Box 9)
  - Rasho-mon, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Royal Hunt of the Sun, 1970-1971 (Box 9)
  - St. Joan (Box 9)
  - The Adding Machine (Box 9)
  - After Dark, 1936-1937 (Box 9)
  - After the Fall, 1974 (Box 9)
  - The American Dream, 1972 (Box 9)
  - Androcles and the Lion, 1934 (Box 9)
  - Angel Street, 1948 (Box 9)
  - Another Part of the Forest (Box 9)
  - Arms and the Man, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Arsenic and Old Lace, 1942 (Box 9)
  - The Ascent of F-6 (Box 9)
  - Bad Habits, 1976 (Box 9)
  - Bell, Book, and Candle (Box 9)
  - The Adding Machine, 1953-1954 (Box 9)
  - Reviews (Box 9)
  - After the Fall (Box 9)
  - 2 untitled scripts (Box 9)
  - untitled [misc. clippings and photographs] (Box 9)
- Accession UA2014-0038
  - The Medium (Opera), January 1985 (Box 10)
  - Romeo and Juliet, February 1986 (Box 10)
  - Past Grand Knight, December 1985 (Box 10)
  - The Great American Cheese Sandwich, March 1985 (Box 10)
  - Clouds, November 1984 (Box 10)
  - The Good Woman of Setzuan, October 1984 (Box 10)
  - God and the Little Prince, March 1984 (Box 10)
  - Exposures Script, Fall 1983 (Box 10)
  - Production Notebook, Larry Lang, 1983 (Box 10)
  - Exposures, December 1983 (Box 10)
  - Grandma Duck is Dead!, August 1983 (Box 10)
  - Women in Theater: Speaking Out of Character and Original Sin, March 1983 (Box 10)
  - Gallilieo, October 1982 (Box 10)
  - Constitution and Bylaws, Stage Manager's Manual, 1984-1985 (Box 10)
- Accession UA2018.0093, 1982 and undated
  - Posters for Misalliance, Comedy of Errors, Uncommon Women and Others, and the Good Woman of Setzuan, 1982 and undated